我叫Oliver Queen
My name is Oliver Queen.
经历岛上地狱般的五年后
After five years on a hellish island,
我回来了 心怀一个目标...
I have come home with only one goal...
拯救这座城市
to save my city.
但为此我不能再像以前一样杀戮
But to do so, I can't be the killer I once was.
为了祭奠我的好友 我必须重塑自己
To honor my friend's memory, I must be someone else.
Thomas Merlyn之墓 1985-2013
我必须伪装自身
I must be something else.
"绿箭侠" 前情提要...
Previously on "Arrow"...
该做决定了 Oliver
Time to choose, Oliver.
谁生谁死
Who lives and who dies.
因为再过30秒 我就会把她俩都杀了
Because in 30 seconds, I will shoot them both.
你的目的已经达到了!
You got what you came for!
看来你选好了 时间到
I guess you made your choice. Time's up.
不!
No!
你敢给我注射 我就杀了你
If you stick that in me, I'll kill you.
不 Roy兄弟 你会为我杀戮
No, brother Roy, you'll kill for me.
你从哪得到奇迹药的?
Where'd you get the mirakuru?
这是一份礼物 我要用它来
It was a gift. A gift I would use
拯救这座城市
to save this city from itself.
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: Tracy
时间轴: 潇妹纸
翻译: 初见 yjk8654 水果哥 Tracy
校对: 潇妹纸
哇 啊!
Whoa, oh, ahh!
啊! 哦!
Ahh! Oh!
带骷髅面具的男人是谁?! 快说
The man in the skull mask, who is he?!
我不知道!
I-I don't know!
你是这里街头最大的毒贩
You're the biggest street dealer in crescent circle.
这里发生的一切你都了如指掌
You know everything that goes on over there.
他是谁?!
Who is he?!
我以前没见过他!
I ain't seen the guy before!
带着骷髅面具 我真的不知道!
A skull mask, are you freaking kidding me?!
别这样 我还在假释期!
Come on, man, I'm still on parole!
结束了
Not anymore.
绿箭侠 第二季第十集
中心城市长发言人已证实
A spokesman for the central city mayor's office confirmed
五周前S.T.A.R.实验室发生的爆炸
the lack of any damage or radioactive fallout
并未造成放射性尘埃泄露
from the explosion that rocked S.T.A.R. Labs five weeks ago.
Felicity还没回来吗?
Is Felicity not back yet?
她说想再照顾Barry几天
She said she wanted to spend a few more days with Barry.
他的情况有好转了吗?
Any improvement in his condition?
还在昏迷
Still comatose.
今天晚上收获如何?
How'd it go out there tonight?
与前几天在新月城的
Same as every other pointed conversation
那些下三滥说的一样
I have with these lowlifes in Crescent circle.
没人...
Nobody...
见过带着骷髅面具的人
has seen a man in a skull mask.
但他还在逍遥法外
But he's still out there.
Oliver 过去的五周
Oliver, for the past five weeks,
你用尽全力想要找到那个人
you've pushed yourself pretty hard looking for this guy.
奇迹药他手上 Diggle!
He has the mirakuru, Diggle!
你见过要杀掉被注射的人
I mean, you saw what it took to kill one guy
是多么不容易
that had been injected.
要用一栋大楼才能压垮他
We practically had to drop a building on him.
所以如果他们有十人 一百人
So imagine ten or a hundred,
一千人 怎么办
imagine a thousand.
你说Roy被注射了
You said Roy was injected.
是的
Yeah.
我从没看过你这么恐惧
I've just never seen you spooked like this before.
有件事应该告诉你
That should tell you something.
Shado总是对我说 我不会死在这里
Shado always told me that I wouldn't die here.
但回头想想 我发现
But looking back, I realized
她从来没有对自己说过这句话
that she never once said that about herself.
Shado之墓
希望她和她爸爸团聚了
I just hope she's with her father now.
给你
Here, kid.
她会希望你留着它的
She'd want you to have that.
她真正在乎的是你
You're the one she cared for.
Slade啊...
Slade...
嘿 Ollie 让他一个人静一静
Hey, Ollie, just give him space.
我不能再骗他了 Sara
I can't keep lying to him, Sara.
我要告诉她Shado死亡的真相
I need to tell him how Shado really died.
是Ivo开枪杀了Shado
Ivo killed Shado. He pulled the trigger.
因为我选择救你
Because I chose to save you.
他需要知道真相
He needs to know the truth.
- 等等 Ollie 他...  - 放开我
- Wait, Ollie, he...  - Get off me.
他手里现在有奇迹药
He has the mirakuru in his system now.
那又有什么关系?
What does that have to do with anything?
日本人在成千上百个人身上
Look, the Japanese, they experimented
做实验才研制出了奇迹药
on hundreds of men working to develop mirakuru.
我读过他们的报告
and I read the research.
那些死去的人?
The people who died?
他们算是幸运的
They were the lucky ones.
那些活下来的人 身陷残缺
The ones who survived, they were deformed.
身体和精神上的残缺
Either their bones or their minds.
他们变得面目全非
They became someone else.
你叫我过来就是为了喝酒?
You summoned me here for a drink?
看来你还打扮了一番
You certainly look dressed for it.
不 我... 要去约会
No, I... have a date.
你在忙什么呢?
What are you working on?
我在调查Sebastian Blood
Something to do with Sebastian Blood.
据说他是Starling市的下一任市长
AKA the next mayor of Starling city.
也许他当不上
Well, maybe he shouldn't be.
- 这话怎讲?  - 我做了一些
- What does that mean?  - I've just been doing
调查 Blood与兰福德精神病学研究所
some investigating. Blood had a connection
有点瓜葛
to the Langford Psychiatric Institute.
就是那个被神秘
The one that burnt down under very
烧毁的研究所
mysterious circumstances.
- 警察抓到纵火犯了吗?  - 没有
- Do the police suspect arson?  - No.
警察说调查毫无结果
They're saying that it's inconclusive.
而且Blood还认识Cyrus Gold...
But Blood also knew Cyrus Gold...
他曾开枪打死四个警察
the man that shot and killed four police officers.
Laurel 你要把这些给谁看?
Laurel, where are you going with this?
不知道 但我得走了
I don't know. But I do have to go.
我要迟到了
I'm going to be late.
谁今晚有幸与你相约?
So who's the lucky guy?
是Sebastian Blood
Sebastian Blood.
他应该荣膺市长 请大家与我一起
He's the man we need to see in the mayor's office. So, please, join me in our efforts
欢迎Starling市之子
to send Starling's favorite son there.
为Sebastian Blood干杯 谢谢他带领Starling市
To Sebastian Blood. Sebastian for Starling.
谢谢 Oliver
Thank you, Oliver.
不仅是因为你对我的支持
And not just for your support,
更是为了我们的友谊
but also for your friendship.
感谢大家的到来
And thank all of you for coming.
刚才Oliver称我为Starling市之子
You know, when Oliver calls me a son of Starling city,
这样说的确没错
it feels like the literal truth.
我曾是无家可归的孤儿
I was a street orphan,
是这座城市养育了我
and this city raised me as one of its own.
我能有今天的一切 都是因为Starling市这个大家庭的帮助
I am the man that I am today because of my Starling city family.
所以我应该有所回报了
So it's time that I start to give back.
谢谢你们的支持
So thank you all for your support.
演讲很精彩 Ollie
Nice speech, Ollie.
你什么时候对政治感兴趣了?
Who knew you cared so much about politics?
哦 我关心这座城市 而且...
Well, I care about the city, and...
Sebastian现在算是我的朋友
Sebastian has become something of a friend.
很显然 他混的如鱼得水
He's got a way of doing that, apparently.
一点没错
That's very cute.
哦 对了 Roy怎么样?
Speaking of which, how's Roy?
还是那么英俊 深沉
Handsome, brooding, usual.
你怎么关心起来我男朋友了?
Why is my boyfriend such a topic of interest?
哦 Thea 他的偶像给了他一支箭 我只是...
Well, Thea, his idol put an arrow in him, and I just...
想知道没遇到其他的麻烦吧
wanted to make sure there weren't any lingering issues.
天啊 听你这么说我才发现
Oh, my god. Now that I think about it,
他今天早上做了一件很奇怪的事情
you know, he did something completely out of character this morning.
什么事?
What?
他按时来上班了
He showed up for work on time.
Thea! 哦...
Thea! Oh, it's...
派对太棒了
it's just wonderful.
很高兴能尽到市民的责任
Proud to my civic duty.
我真为你骄傲
No, I'm the one who's proud.
你把Oliver的... 爱好变成了
You've taken Oliver's... hobby, and turned it into
一项成功的事业
a successful business.
- 爱好?  - 哦 宝贝
- Hobby?  - Oh, sweetheart.
Oliver啊
Oliver.
啊
Ah.
谢谢你刚才的称赞
Thank you so much for your kind words.
我只是实话实说
I'm just speaking the truth.
哦 失陪一下 有个朋友来了
Oh, forgive me, a friend just walked in.
- 嗨  - 嗨
- Hi.  - Hi.
很高兴你能来
Glad you could come.
Sebastian邀请了我
Sebastian invited me.
是的 我听说你们俩整天在一起
Yes, I hear the two of you have been spending a lot of time together.
我们只是朋友
We're just friends.
他也这么想吗?
Does he know that?
啊哦
Uh-oh.
你还有什么可犹豫的?
What's holding you back?
有时候我摸不透Sebastian
Sometimes I feel like I don't know the real Sebastian.
他让我想起了你
He reminds me a little of you that way.
嗯
Hmm.
自由
Freedom.
独立
Liberty.
正义
Justice.
人们已经被腐败的政府
Long have the people of this city suffered
自私自利的政客...
under the shackles of a corrupt government...
还有傀儡般的游说者
slaves to self-interested politicians
折磨得够长时间了...
and their lobbyist puppeteers.
我向你们所有人宣战
I declare war on them all.
大楼里有人吗?
Anyone in the building?
有清洁工和一些上晚班的
Cleaning crew and a group of bankers
银行工作人员
working out a late night deal.
能帮我进入警察局和消防队的网络吗?
Can you patch me into police and fire?
这就进
I'm on it.
Diggle啊...
Diggle...
嘿 兄弟 我可不擅长电脑
Hey, man, this is not my thing.
没法上去 都被困住了
Can't get up there. Everything's blocked.
19层还有人没出来
You've still got people on the 19th floor.
温度太高 我们进不去
It's too hot. We're falling back.
救命!
Help!
Gary还在里面
Gary's still back there.
快去安全地带
Get to safety.
伸手过来
Give me your hand.
谢谢
Thank you.
嘿
Hey.
你还好吧?
You ok?
你要去哪?
Where you going?
去发动飞机
To the plane, to get geared up.
为什么?
For what?
Ivo还在这里
Ivo is still out there.
我要去找他
I'm going to find him, and when I do,
我要把他撕成碎片
I'm going to cut pieces of him.
你不能去 Ivo有一船的手下
You can't. Ivo has a ship
他们都是杀手 不管你以前
full of men, of killers. And I don't care
有多英勇 你不能以一当百
what you did before, you can't take them all out.
你现在应该找个安全的地方躲着 等他现身
Your only play here is to find safe ground and wait him out.
你当然会这么说
Well, of course you would say that.
你为他卖命
You were working for him.
你还在为他卖命
You're probably still working for him!
嘿 嘿!
Hey, hey!
她不是的
She's not.
别拦着我 小子
Get out of my way, kid.
我们先冷静一下
Look, let's just take it easy...
我说了...
I said...
别拦着我
get out of my way.
你没事吧? 昨晚很累吧
You ok? Long night.
嗯 新闻上说爆炸犯没有偷钱
Yeah. News report said the bomber didn't steal any money.
我想他只是想昭告天下
I think this guy just wants to make a statement.
一小时前网上就传播开来了
That went online an hour ago.
他发表了足足300页反政府声明
His manifesto. 300 pages of anti-government hate.
你觉得这个疯子跟那个骷髅面具男有关系吗?
You think this psycho's any way connected to our psycho in the skull mask?
这个人是单独行动
This guy has a completely separate agenda.
他是匹独狼
He's a lone wolf, but we need
但是我们必须在他锁定下个目标前找到他
to find him before he finds his next target.
我从炸弹上开找线索 每个人都是独一无二的
I'd start with the bomb. Everyone's unique.
也许能找到有关他的线索
Maybe we can get some kind of signature on the guy.
但是弹片残余在警察手里
But the bomb residue is with the SCPD.
幸运的是 我们在警局里有内应
Fortunately we have an in with one of the officers at the department.
我以为你还要在中心城多留几天呢
I thought you were staying in central city for a few more days.
我看到了关于爆炸的新闻
I got a news alert about the bombing.
坐着今早的第一班火车就赶回来了
Caught the first train out this morning.
太好了
Good.
我们需要你
We need you here.
Barry的状况如何?
How's Barry?
呃 还在昏睡中
Ah, he's still sleeping.
我比较喜欢用昏睡 而不用昏迷
I prefer sleeping to coma,
因为昏迷听起来不爽
because coma sounds, you know, not fun.
我去联系Lance警探
I'll reach out to detective Lance.
嘿
Hey.
- 我们约好吃午饭了吗?  - 没有
- Did we have a lunch today?  - No.
我刚好在附近
I was just in the neighborhood.
想来拜访一下 要是不凑巧的话
Thought I'd stop by. But if this is
我其他时间再来
a bad time, I mean, I can always come back.
没有 他们还在布置
Oh, no, not at all, they're still setting up out there.
哇哦
Wow.
真是一位让人刮目相看的街头孤儿啊
This is pretty impressive for a street orphan.
你是不是觉得我昨晚的言辞有点过了?
Are you suggesting I spread it on a bit too thick last night?
没有
No.
只是...
It's just...
Laurel 要是有什么事情
Laurel, if there's something on your mind,
尽管直说
Give it voice.
我不介意
I don't bite.
我说话算数
I promise.
- 你也知道我父亲在警局工作  - 是的
- You know my father's with the department.  - Yes.
他说他和他的同事遇袭时
He said the suspect that he was investigating
调查的那个嫌疑人
when he and his partner were attacked
叫做Cyrus Gold的人
was a man named Cyrus Gold.
Cyrus Gold啊...
Cyrus Gold...
曾经是牧师
was a preacher
他当时在我被收养的孤儿院工作
at the orphanage where I was raised.
Cyrus那时是我最好的朋友...
Cyrus was a very good friend to me...
就像兄长一样待我
like an older brother.
说实话 他更像位长者
Or even a father figure, to be honest.
他曾是我第一个愿意开口讲话的人
He was the first person I said a word to,
当时我已经一个月没开口讲过话了
and this was after a month of not speaking at all.
你经常说起孤儿时的经历
You talk a lot about being an orphan,
但是却从没提起过你的父母
But you don't talk about your parents.
你对他们有何了解?
Did you know them?
我父亲是个阴郁的人
My father was a very unhappy man.
有天晚上 他喝了很多威士忌酒回家
One night he came home soaked in whiskey.
他又把工作丢了 所以他打断了我母亲的手臂
He lost his job again, so he broke her arm.
我想要阻止他 却被他推到一边
I tried to stop him, but he threw me off.
之后就看到母亲拿着他的枪
And the next thing I saw was my mother holding my father's gun in her hand.
我亲眼看着母亲向他开枪
And I watched her shoot him.
她恐慌极了
She panicked.
在警察到来之前就匆匆逃跑
Ran and was gone before the police even arrived.
那是我最后一次见到他们
It was the last time I saw my parents.
很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我不知道...
I don't know...
Cyrus为何会变成这样
why Cyrus' life took the turn that it did,
很抱歉
I'm sad to say.
我只知道...
All I know...
他曾帮助过一个恐慌无助的小男孩
is that he helped a very young,
让他重新开口讲话
very frightened boy find his voice again.
抱歉
Ahem. I'm sorry.
晚点好吗?
More later?
发票
圣沃克医院
Maya Resik
支付人 Sebastian Blood
Starling市Oakwood街5531号
邮编 98114
我都没听到你进来了
Didn't hear you come in.
抱歉 我... 我来早了
Yeah, sorry, I... I got here early.
我就是想在午饭之前把这些箱子拆好
I just want to get these crates unpacked before lunch.
你还好吧?
Are you ok?
是啊 我挺好的
Yeah, I'm fine.
只是... 最近睡眠有点不足
Just... I haven't been sleeping much lately.
脑子里乱七八糟的
I got a lot on my mind.
想跟我聊聊吗?
You want to talk about it?
聊什么?
Talk about what?
过去五周里你身上发生的事
Whatever's been going on with you the last five weeks.
看啊 我不挺好的吗
Look, I'm fine.
自从被绿箭侠射伤后
Ever since the Arrow shot you,
你就变得怪怪的 Roy
you've been acting really weird, Roy.
无论是对我 还是其他事
With me, with everything.
不关绿箭侠的事
This isn't about the Arrow.
是因为我吗?
Is it me?
还是我们之间怎么了?
Is it us?
听我说 我真的只是想尽快恢复正常 好吗?
Look, I really just want to get through this, ok?
好的
Ok.
有需要我帮忙的 尽管开口
Let me know if there's anything I can do to help.
Thea啊
Thea.
你一直在帮我
You do help.
一直都在
Every day.
不得不说 现在你是唯一
And honestly, right now you're the only thing
能让我不崩溃的人
that's keeping me together.
我只是尽力而为
I do what I can.
我怎么会这么幸运呢?
How did I get to be so lucky?
因为... 你偷了我的包
You... stole my purse.
没错
Hmm.
Roy啊?!
Roy?!
- Thea 你没事吧?  - 没事
- Thea,are you ok?  - Yeah.
天啊 你的手臂...
Oh, your arm...
呃 伤口看起来很深
Um, that looks really deep.
可能需要缝针 我去楼下拿急救箱
It might need stitches. Um, I'm going to go downstairs
你能行吗?
and get the first aid kit, ok?
没事
Ok.
大多数警察
You know, most cops,
都是在巡逻车的后座跟线人见面
they meet their informants in the backseat of a cruiser
或者是咖啡馆什么的 但是...
or maybe a coffee shop or something, but...
你怎么戴上面具了?
What's with the mask?
- 朋友送的  - 你竟然有朋友?
- Gift from a friend.  - You got friends?
我要的东西带来了吗?
Did you bring me what I asked for?
里面有取证部门在爆炸现场找到所有东西的样本
That's a sample of everything the CSU collected from the blast.
有融化了的玻璃 爆炸物的碎片
There's melted glass, multiple explosive fragments,
还有爆破物残料 看起来像硝化甘油
and trace residue, and it looks like nitroglycerine.
看起来不像是个普通的疯子在作案
Which means that we're dealing with more than just a basement nutjob.
他受过训练
Someone with training.
谢谢你 警探
Thank you, detective.
我也需要你帮个忙
I need a favor, too.
杀死我同事和搭档的那个罪该万死的人...
The son of a bitch who killed my men, my partner...
他死了
He's dead.
还有给他通风报信的人
And whoever tipped him off, told him we were coming,
他还没事
he's doing just fine.
需要我做什么?
What do you need?
我辖区所有警察的通话记录
Cell phone records for every cop in my precinct.
你觉得有内鬼?
You think there's a leak in the department?
我觉得通话记录能让一切明了
I think those phone records are the only way
你的那位金发朋友
to know for sure, and your blonde friend,
她的电脑技术不是很好嘛
she's pretty good with computers.
我会找她帮忙的...
I'll ask her...
Dc-52向总局汇报 市中心发生爆炸!
Dc-52 to central, 10-80, downtown!
他又行动了
He's hit again.
Starling市行政大楼
Starling city municipal building.
- 地址告诉我  - 我给你比地址还有用的...
- Give me a location.  - I'll give you one better...
我正在搜索附近的信号塔
I'm checking the surrounding cell towers.
爆炸前两秒钟
There was a GSM spike
曾经出现3800兆赫的定位脉冲
of 3,800 megahertz two seconds before the blast.
这个频率甚至比
That frequency's way outside the approved frequency
美国航运频率还高
for U.S. Carriers.
信号在转移 他乘了交通工具
Signal's moving. I think he's mobile.
地址给我
Give me an intersection.
你正前方400米处
Right in front of you, 400 meters.
我看到他了
I see him.
第67街左转
Turn left on 67th.
Felicity 我跟丢了
Felicity, I've lost him.
什么?
What?
我也是 等下
Me, too, hold on.
发现他了 Gerrard街左转
Got him. Bank left on Gerrard street.
你差不多就在他正上方
You're almost right on top of him.
不是他 Felicity 你的信号定位错了
It's not him, Felicity. You picked up the wrong signal.
什么? 我以为... 他一定是干扰信号了
What? I thought... he must have scrambled the signal.
无所谓了
It doesn't matter.
他逃掉了
He is gone.
到底怎么回事?
What happened?
他使用蜂窝技术引爆炸弹
He's using cellular technology to detonate his bombs.
而且 他很擅长隐藏信号
Clearly, his expertise extends to obscuring that signal.
Felicity 你的能力应该比他强啊?
Felicity, your expertise was supposed to trump his.
你什么意思?
Excuse me?
有话直说 Oliver
If you have something to say to me, Oliver, say it.
人们的性命危在旦夕 希望你能够把思绪从中心城收回来
People are dying. So I would like you to pull your head
对这里的事上上心
out of central city and get back in the game.
还是先把你的头绪理清吧
Sure, right after you get yours out of your ass.
- 你说什么?  - 够了
- Excuse me?  - All right.
大家淡定一下
Maybe we should just take a breath here.
不行 我要弄明白 你提中心城
No, wait, I want to know, what exactly was that crack
到底是什么意思?
about central city meant to imply?
第一起爆炸案发生的时候 你不在这里
When the first bomb went off, you weren't here.
第二起爆炸案发生的时候 你又给我指错了路
And when the second bomb went off, you sent me the wrong way.
是你先跟丢了的!
After you didn't catch him in the first place!
别因为你的失误埋怨我
Don't blame me because you didn't have it tonight.
我出去透透透气
I need some air.
冒着掉头的危险也得说句话啊...
At the risk of me getting my head knocked off...
互相埋怨可不能
Playing the blame game's not going to help us
帮助我们抓到他
catch this son of a bitch.
半途而废也不能
Neither is doing things halfway.
你觉得她会这样吗 Oliver?
Is that what you think's going on here, Oliver?
你觉得她不上心?
You think she was distracted?
她没有尽心尽力?
She wasn't giving it her all?
她差点让我撞到公交车上 Diggle
She almost ran me into a bus, Diggle.
你觉得呢?
What do you think?
我觉得你是因为Barry Allen
I think you didn't have a problem
才埋怨Felicity的状态
with Felicity's performance until she met Barry Allen.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你很不正常 Slade
You're not well, Slade.
我知道了
Hey...
是奇迹药水
It's the mirakuru.
它扰乱了你的思维
It's messing with your head.
天快黑了 我们得赶紧扎营
It's going to be dark soon. We should make camp.
怎么了? 你还好吧?
What's going on? You ok?
没事 只不过一受凉胳膊就疼
Yeah, it's just, arm still hurts when it's cold.
医生给的止疼药我还给弄丢了
And I lost the pain meds that the doctor gave me.
你的伤怎么样了?
How's yours healing up?
时好时坏
Ah, you know, good days and bad.
等会聊
I'll see you later.
嘿
Hey.
不可思议
Pretty crazy.
是啊 你还好吧?
Yeah. You doing all right?
你要是有空的话 帮个忙
I thought I could use your help, if you have a second.
你现在是地区检察官了
You being at the DA's office now,
就像谈家事一样 过来
it's almost like you joined the family business. Come on.
我在找一个叫"Maya Resik"的人
I'm trying to find someone
我在网上搜过
named "Maya Resik." I searched the internet,
查了车管所和社保记录 没有任何信息
the dmv records, social security... nothing.
找这样一个鬼魂干嘛?
Why are you looking for a ghost?
Sebastian在给她钱
Sebastian's paying her bills.
一个不存在的女人
A woman who doesn't seem to exist,
我觉得很可疑
I find that suspicious.
你男朋友不怀好意
Thinking that your boyfriend's up to no good,
我应该比你还上心
that's typically more my thing than yours.
准确地说 他不是我男朋友
Oh, he's not exactly my boyfriend.
那窥探他的生活
Well, that makes digging into his life
也就失去了些乐趣
a little less fun, then.
等等 Laurel
Hey, Laurel.
如果我帮你查出点东西
If I bring you something back,
我要知道为什么
you know I'm going to want to know why.
你会的
Of course you are.
你回来的正是时候 刚好赶上表演
Ah, you're just in time to see the show.
他在干吗?
What's he doing?
把整个城市的人聚集起来
Bringing the city together.
要是我没弄错的话 竞选
And if I'm not mistaken, campaigning.
明天晚上 我要在城市大厦召开第一次联合大会
Tomorrow night, I am holding starling's first ever unity rally at city plaza.
我们要向世界证明 这座伟大城市的人民
We are going to show the world that the people of this great city
不会向恐怖势力妥协
will not back down to terrorists.
他想自杀
He's committing suicide and he just invited
还要叫上全市的人和他一起
the entire city to join him.
你是Sebastian的朋友
Sebastian's your friend.
你能不能劝劝他?
Can't you talk him out of this, Oliver?
就是今天
Well, that day is now.
他不会听我的
Well, he won't listen to me.
Sebastian Blood议员...
Sebastian Blood...
明晚的集会
This rally tomorrow night,
你要取消
you need to call it off.
绿箭侠亲自来给我送行
The starling city vigilante paying a visit to wave me off.
我很荣幸
I'm flattered.
Mr. Blood 这次集会
This event, Mr. Blood,
你应该知道 是玩火自焚
You might as well be painting a giant bulls eye on your chest.
这座城市需要团结
This city needs to come together.
而我会告诉他们怎么做
And I need to show them how.
你死了 就什么都做不了
You won't be able to show them anything if you're dead.
每天晚上 你冒着生命危险
Every night, you risk your life
保卫这座城市的人民
for the people of this city.
我怎么能作壁上观?
How can you expect me to do any less?
你就不顾参加集会人们的生命吗?
And what about the lives of the people coming to your rally?
这次集会
This rally is about Starling City
是要让Starling市坚强起来
standing up and declaring with one voice
告诉人们恐惧中的生活不能叫生活
that living afraid isn't living.
我不会告诉市民们待在家里
I won't send a contrary message to people
担惊受怕
telling them to stay home, to stay scared.
我意已决
I've made my decision.
听好了 议员
That's the thing, Alderman...
明晚发生的事
Whatever happens tomorrow night,
并非你能决定的
it's not up to you.
# 我醒来了 而她已不在 #
# I wake up and she's not there #
是Fazekas女士啊
Ah, Mrs. Fazekas.
给你外甥准备的火车刚刚到
The train set for your nephew
他一定爱死了
just came in. He's going to love it.
您真是太敬业了 Scheffer先生
Oh. You are a miracle worker, Mr. Scheffer.
我应该给你多少钱?
How much do I owe you?
50就好
$50 even.
销售税就不用了
Forget the sales tax.
明晚会去参加议员的集会吗?
Going to the alderman's unity rally tomorrow night?
当然不会错过
I wouldn't miss it.
无视爆炸给城市带来的困扰
Gathered here despite the rash of bombings
而聚集在这里
that have plagued the city,
有人说Sebastian Blood召开的这次集会
Some have called Sebastian Blood's unity rally
是他为了竞选市长组织的
a cynical and dangerous pr stunt
一次危险而不负责任的公关噱头
for his mayoral campaign.
但是参与的人数还在增加
But the crowd continues to grow.
我劝过他了
Tried to get him to stand down.
他回击的时候和你一样固执
He seems as stubborn as you when it comes to fighting back.
- 不光是回击的时候  - 是不以后
- Or everything.  - Hey, is this how
你俩就一直这样了?
it's going to be with you two from now on?
我们应该去集会现场
Maybe we should just head down to the rally.
不一定要去
Maybe we won't have to.
我分析了Lance给的爆炸残留物
I analyzed the bomb remnants we got from Lance.
它的设计和以前叫行动的反政府民兵部队
The design's identical to the bombs used by
所使用的炸弹一样
an anti government militia group called the Movement.
幸运的是 我们可以黑进他们活跃的留言板
Lucky for us, they have a very active and hackable message board.
其中一个很多产的粉丝的IP地址就在Starling
One of their most prolific fans has an ip address right here in Starling.
- 在哪?  - 那台电脑在一家纪念品商店
- Tell me.  - The computer's in a local souvenir shop.
所找少年的用户名叫Shrapnel
The whackadoo in question goes by the username Shrapnel.
需要后援吗？
You want back-up?
不 你去集会
No, I need you at the rally.
掩护我们的基地
Cover our bases.
这都是给我的?
Is this all for me?
不 是我的 警察局的通话记录
No, for me. SCPD phone records.
你为什么要查警局的通话记录?
Why are you going through the department's phone records?
我查了你那个不算男朋友的男朋友
Um, so I checked up on your not exactly boyfriend.
然后呢? 有什么发现吗?
And? Did you find anything?
当然 我发现他不是个好人
Yeah, it turns out he's a hell of a guy.
替她姑姑付钱...
Covers the expenses of his dear aunt...
他姑姑就是Maya Resik
Your Maya Resik.
如果Sebastian还有其他家人
If Sebastian has other family,
那他为什么在孤儿院?
then why was he placed in an orphanage?
也许是他的Maya姑姑脑子有问题
Well, maybe 'cause aunt Maya is nuttier than a snickers bar.
她是圣沃克斯医院的病人
She's a patient at St.Walker's hospital.
那是家精神病院 你根本不会去查的地方
It's a mental institution, it's the kind you don't check out of.
你到底要不要告诉我发生了什么?
Now, listen, you going to tell me what this is all about?
他似乎不太正常
Something about him just seems off.
Laurel 替自己唯一
Laurel, there is nothing sinister
在世的亲人付钱
about a guy who is covering the expenses
没什么比这更可怕的了
of his only living relative.
而事实是 这很好
The truth is, it's kind of nice.
我要去城市大厦了
Listen, I gotta get to city plaza.
Pike要召集所有人手
Pike wants all hands at this unity rally.
你不会去的 对吧?
You're not going, right?
我不去了 我还要继续深入调查
No, I need to look into this more.
Laurel 他看起来是个好孩子
Laurel, he seems like a good guy
他配得上你
and you deserve good.
别纠结于这些
Ok, so stop looking for reasons
又把自己撇出去了
to talk yourself out of it.
求你了
Please.
Blood议员 这很危险你知道吗?
Alderman Blood, is this not dangerous?
恐怕是的
I'm afraid so.
你为什么要把这么多人聚集在这当活靶子?
Why are you gathering all these people here to be targets?
稍后我会一一回答你的问题
Please, I'll get to all of your questions later.
感谢你们能来
Thank you all for coming.
砰
Boom.
你已经死了
You're dead.
你敢往前走一步
Or will be if you take one more step
或者稍微动一下就真死了
or move a single muscle.
那你就看不到接下来的表演了
And then you'll miss the show.
候选人Blood的集会
Candidate Blood's unity rally.
我在那儿装好了50磅的烈性旋风炸药
Already rigged with 50 pounds of RDX high explosives.
和我店里石膏板后边装的可不一样
Not unlike what's packed inside the drywall of my store.
市民们觉得Sebastian Blood能保证他们的安全
This city thinks Sebastian Blood can keep them safe.
今晚 他们会明白
Tonight, they learn that the only thing politicians
政治家们只关心他们的前途
care about protecting is their jobs.
- Felicity  - 在
- Felicity.  - Here.
你抓住他了?
Did you get him?
没有 他说他的爆炸装置
No. He said he rigged the plaza
能炸毁整栋大楼
with an explosive device.
Oliver 那人山人海
Oliver, it's crazy-town there.
炸弹可能在任何地方
That bomb could be anywhere.
我能缩小范围 给我接通Diggle
I can narrow that down. Get me Diggle.
说吧
Go.
Shrapnel说他在周围装好了旋风炸药
Shrapnel said he ringed the perimeter with RDX.
我去找
I'm on it.
你在去大厦的路上吧?
You're heading to the plaza, too, right?
还没有
Not yet.
我要你把关于这个商店所有的东西找出来
I need you to pull me up anything you can on the store.
规划设计图 示意图 所有东西
Blue prints, permit schematics, anything.
怎么了?
What's going on?
Shrapnel给我留了个惊喜
Shrapnel left behind a surprise.
说他在石膏板后边也放好了炸药
Said he packed the drywall with explosives,
但是要触发需要...
but the trigger needs to be...
需要连接到电源
Would need to be hooked up to some sort of power supply.
导火索连接到商店的电路
That's assuming that the detonator's connected
而且不是汽车电池那种独立的电流
to the store's electricity and not something independent
我明白 但是没什么帮助
like a car battery. I know, not helpful.
你确定要我做这个?
You sure you want me doing this?
我的思路可能不在这场斗争里
My head might not exactly be in the game.
Felicity! 别闹!
Felicity!
那栋楼是70年代建的
The building was built in the seventies.
这是好消息
That's good news.
那时的建筑里线路有很多缺陷
The wiring in a lot of construction back then is defective.
如果你切断了一条线
So if you sever one wire,
就会烧断整栋楼的保险丝
it will blow fuses in the entire building
然后切断炸弹的电源
and shot off power to the bomb.
注意了 我看见保险盒了
Hold tight. I see a fuse box.
Oliver 小心点
Oliver, be careful.
Oliver 你在吗?
Oliver?
Oliver啊?
没事 我没事
It's all right. I'm all right.
去集会吧
Get to the rally.
去帮Diggle 我这就去
Help Diggle. I'm on my way.
Thea 我真觉得不该来这里
Thea, I really don't think coming here was a good idea.
不会有事的
It's gonna be fine.
我们去找Roy
Let's just go find Roy.
请安静
Please, please.
应该给你们鼓掌喝彩
You're the ones who deserve an ovation.
8个月前 这座城市从毁灭性的袭击中存活下来...
8 months ago this city survived a devastating attack...
但是我们站起来了
But we rose up.
你们站起来了
You rose up
并且团结起来 就像今晚一样
and banded together, just like we are tonight.
Dig 我到了
Dig, I'm on site.
我在东边 应该是找到触发器了
I'm on the east side. Think I found the trigger.
并向全世界证明
And prove to the world
我们是打不倒的
that we cannot be broken.
这座城市的人们
That the people of this city
非常坚强
are too strong.
不是炸弹和地震
And that no bomb and no earthquake
就能摧毁的
is strong enough to tear us apart.
Oliver说这个地方
Oliver said that the whole place
到处都是炸药
was ringed with explosives.
在这个音响设备里
It's in the sound equipment.
这就是触发器
and this is the trigger.
Shrapnel通过手机信号启动它
Shrapnel activates it by cellular transmission.
听着 没必要拆除它 废掉它就行
Listen, we don't have to disarm it, just disable it.
我可以
I can do that.
我想是的
I think.
希望是
I hope.
Felicity 听好 你要小心
Felicity, listen, you be careful.
他也许用了保障措施
He probably put in a safeguard.
进行干预
Tampering with it
也许会触发死人键
will set off a deadman's switch.
那个词真压抑
That's a really depressing term.
而且有性别歧视之嫌
And a little bit sexist.
走开
Step away.
否则谁都活不成
Or we all know how this ends.
Dig啊!
Dig!
妈妈!
Mom!
我没事 我没事
I'm OK. I'm OK.
把弓放下
Drop the bow.
我在Starling市埋满了炸药
I've got charges planted all over Starling.
我按了这个 就会爆炸
I drop this stick, they all blow.
你听到我刚才说的话了吗?
Did you just hear what I said?
听到了
Yep.
嘿
Hey.
你妈妈怎么样了?
How's your mom?
她没事 有点吓到了
She's fine. Just a little shooken up.
你救了她
You saved her.
是我走运
I got lucky.
那不是运气
That wasn't luck.
那简直不可能
That was impossible.
你知道有妈妈把车抬起来救自己的孩子吗?
You know those stories of mom's lifting cars to save their kids?
肾上腺素飙升时 啥都能做到
Things you can do when adrenaline hits.
我... 我就是那样
It was... It was one of those.
你的手臂
Your arm.
连个疤痕都没留下
There's not even a mark.
是... 我伤口愈合快
It's... I heal fast.
- 没事  - 嗯
- It's fine.  - Right.
我有点累了 今天晚上太多事了
I'm kind of tired. It's been a long night, you know.
我走了
I gotta go.
Roy啊
Roy.
你杀的人越来越少
With you dropping fewer bodies,
Starling市大概应该建一个大点的监狱
Starling city should probably build a bigger jail.
又要去找骷髅面具人吗?
Another night of skull mask hunting?
不是
Not exactly.
你肩膀怎样了?
How's your shoulder?
不严重
Oh, just a through-and-through.
小意思
Walk in the park.
但是Diggle 你还是应该回家休息一下
Still, Diggle, you should go home and get some rest.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你在向我道歉
Are you apologizing to me
还是在跟你的箭袋说话
or were you talking to your quiver?
我又没跟我箭袋发脾气
I didn't snap at my quiver.
你不止是发脾气吧
You kind of more than snapped.
我知道
I know.
很抱歉
And I'm sorry.
我知道奇迹药的事让你很害怕
I understand that this mirakuru thing has you freaked out
而我又在中心城待了太久
and I have been in central city a lot.
Felicity 不是因为那个
Felicity, it's not that.
你在那里的时候
When you are there,
就更让我意识到 这里多需要你
Well, it just made me realize how much I need you here.
开... 开始的时候
In the beg... beginning,
我准备... 我准备自己做这些事
I was just gonna... I was gonna do all of this by myself.
如今有了你和Diggle...
And now with you and Diggle...
我依赖你们
I rely on you.
那是否意味着
Does that mean I have a shot
我有可能成为明星雇员呢?
at employee of the month?
不是
No.
因为你不是我的员工
Because you're not my employee.
你是我的同伴
You're my partner.
Barry会醒来的
Barry's gonna wake up.
当他醒来时 你要在他身边
And when he does, you will be there.
终于有人喜欢我了
I finally have a guy who's interested in me
他却被闪电击中了
and he's struck by lightning,
还处于昏迷中
ends up in a coma.
真神奇
Typical.
也许他梦到你呢
Well, maybe he's dreaming about you.
知道吗 对于处于昏迷的病人
You know, actually there's conflicting cases
是真的在做梦还是产生幻觉
about whether coma patients can in fact dream normally
还不能确定
Or they're more like hallucinating.
谢谢
Thank you.
Sara啊
Sara.
Sara 我知道你在听 回答我
Sara, I know you're listening. Answer me.
事情非常简单 Sara
This is very simple, Sara.
我知道你和你的新朋友有奇迹药
I know you and your new friends have the mirakuru.
就算将这里夷为平地 我也要得到它
You know I will lay waste to this entire island to get it.
去叫Slade
Get Slade.
但不必那样
But it doesn't have to be that way.
我只想要血清
All I want is the serum.
作为交换 我可以向你和你的朋友保证
In exchange, I'll promise you and your friends
你们可以安全离开这个岛
safe passage off this island, I promise.
十天之内 你和你的新朋友
Within 10 days, you and your new friends
就可以到达上海
could be making port in Shanghai.
我也可以派我的手下
The alternative is I send my men
到丛林里找到你们 拿到血清
into the jungle to take the serum from you.
他们奉我的命令 不杀你们
They'll be under orders not to kill any of you.
反而 你们会活着
Instead, you'll remain alive enough
满足我的科学好奇心
for me to indulge my scientific curiosity.
考虑一下吧 Sara
Think about it, Sara.
- 他走了  - 什么?
- He's gone.  - What?
Slade走了 把奇迹药也带走了
Slade's gone and he took the mirakuru with him.
你可以问任何问题
You can ask all the questions you want,
但是估计也问不出什么来
but I wouldn't count on getting anything back.
她也许都不会知道你在她身边
She probably won't even know you're there.
如果你需要什么 我就在楼下
I'll be down the hall if you need anything.
Maya啊?
Maya?
我来跟你谈谈关于你侄子的事
I'm here to talk about your nephew.
有一个男孩
Un buen chico.
Maya 我叫Laurel Lance
Maya, my name's Laurel Lance.
Maya啊?
Maya?
我来跟你谈谈关于你侄子的事
I'm here to talk about your nephew.
有一个男孩
Un buen chico,
Un chico listo,
有一个男孩
Un chico hermoso.
Maya? Maya 知道吗?
Maya? Maya, que chico?
知道吗? Sebastian?
Que chico? Sebastian?
Sebastian啊
Sebastian.
是的 是的 Sebastian Blood
Yes, yes. Sebastian Blood.
总会有人要伤害我们
There will always be those who seek to harm us,
但那不会让我们变弱
but it will not weaken us.
那只会让我们更强大
It will only make us stronger.
做得好 议员
Well done, Alderman.
多亏了你
Thanks to you.
但还是冒了很大的险
Still a very big risk to take.
今晚我们一同支持Starling市
Tonight we both stood up for Starling city.
你和我 如果我们合作
You and me, we can save this city,
就可以拯救这个城市
if we work together.
Maya 你能跟我说说Sebastian的事吗?
Maya, can you talk to me about Sebastian?
没事的 你可以信任我
It's OK. You can trust me.
好吗?
OK?
Sebastian是我的朋友
Sebastian is my friend.
Sebastian是恶魔
Sebastian is the devil.
他把我扔到这里
He the one who put me here.
他让所有人认为我疯了
He made everybody think I'm insane.
但是他为什么那么做?
But why would he do that?
他杀了自己的父亲
He killed his father.
我当时在场
And I was there.
我看见了
I saw it.
天啊
Oh, my god.
Sebastian不是你的侄子
Sebastian isn't your nephew,
他是你儿子
he's your son.
不要相信他的话
Don't trust a word he says.
绝不能相信Sebastian Blood
You can't trust Sebastian Blood.
-=圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hd.cnscg.com/=-
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: Tracy
时间轴: 潇妹纸
翻译: 初见 yjk8654 水果哥 Tracy
校对: 潇妹纸